Tufts Observer UP055
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Tufts Observer, 1996 -- 2000; UP055.025; 1.2 Linear Feet
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-01-27; UP055.025.025.00068 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Winter weather poses challenges for administration. Y2K preparation successful. Drama professor [Michael] McDowell dies. Senate announces much-anticipated meal plan changes, students offered increased variety of dining options. Senior [Jason Potts] seeks to advance scope of CSL [Committee on Student Life] on campus. Men swimmers split weekend. Women swim to two wins over weekend. Men's basketball team bounces back. Women's basketball keeps winning big. Hockey skates to wild win against Johnson and Wales.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-02-03; UP055.025.025.00069 (Box 25)
    Primaries attract Tufts Community. Administration seeks appropriate alcohol emergency policy. Peace Corps ranks Tufts number two. Online book-buying poses problem for students. EPIIC [Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship] events feature accomplished athletes. TUTV personality entertains legions of fans. Swimmers fall flat at Bates. Women end quad as second of Five teams. Men's basketball vanquishes the Bantam Menace. Jumbos [hockey ground the flying dutchman]. Women's b-ball defeats Scots. Men's track wins third quad cup at Bowdoin.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-02-10; UP055.025.025.00070 (Box 25)
    Club sports secures a victory in battle for funding. Senior fund linked to senate cabinet in first appointment. EPIIC symposium highlights accomplished athletes. Tufts engineers compete to build strongest bridge, best canoe. Biology professor [Jan Pechenik] spawns writing workshop. Hockey team loses three close games. Men's basketball cooks Curry. Women's basketball makes statement vs. Continentals.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-02-17; UP055.025.025.00071 (Box 25)
    Incidents of racial vandalism appear on campus. Computer Science department responds to marked increase in student interest. Student leaders voice concerns to trustees. Forum assesses romance language options. REAL [Resumed education for adult learners] senior bridges the generation gap.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-02-24; UP055.025.025.00072 (Box 25)
    Vandalism confounds area schools. Endowment ranked 87th. High incidences of stolen records hindre WMFO's performance. Volunteer vacations expand frther as demand for community service elevates. Senior [Zack Williams] tkaes active role in promoting women's equality. Tufts drama features trip through the ages.Women's track third at championships at Bowdoin. Hockey heads into playoffs chasing away Greyhounds. Men's basketball slashes panthers. Women's basketball has fighting chance.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-03-02; UP055.025.025.00073 (Box 25)
    Administration rejects co-ed housing proposal. Rumors forum sparks campus controversy. Tufts pursues environmental compliance. Substance free housing integrity compromised by unwilling residents. Vendors and senators consider MOPS [Merchants on Points] changes. Beezlebubs prepare for european tour, cd recording postponed. Language chair [Isabelle Naginski] brings passion to romance languages. Men's basketball team harpoons lancers in first round of ECACs. Hockey loses in second round of playoffs to Fitchburg St. Falcons. Men's swimming ends season with fourth place finish at New Englands.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-03-09; UP055.025.025.00074 (Box 25)
    Comedian [Bill] Cosby selected for commencement. Students cast votes in presidential primaries. Mayor, senate campaign for addition to controversial mural. N.Y. Times publisher [Arthus Shulzberger Jr.] to speak. CECA meets with [Vice President Mel] Bernstein. Senate creates PR committee. Shuttle driver's [Ed Marchant] latest stop is Tufts. Women's track sends eight runners to nationals. March madness strikes Medford. Fencing team finishes successful season. Jumbos fall short of ECAC finals, pecked by Fitchburg Falcons.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-04-01; UP055.025.025.00075 (Box 25)
    April Fools Day Issue.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-04-06; UP055.025.025.00076 (Box 25)
    Party ends in arrests. Christian fellowship rejects bisexual member's request. Dean of students search narrowed. [Keisha] Pollack wins Wendall Philips. Survey addresses Tufts' global awareness. Sophomore [Kimbal Hall] sets sights on Olympic team. Alumni invest $10 million in Tufts. Students participate in Census. Track kicks off season at Ellis Oval. Softball trip to Orange, Calif. proves fruitful. Tennis trip down south sends record up to 5-1. Women's lax remains loose. Baseball team steamrolls over Bates, Wentworth, improves to 12-3. Men's lacrosse loses first two NESCAC games of season.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-04-13; UP055.025.025.00077 (Box 25)
    Registration goes online, security considered. Senate nominations contested. Rethinking the police. Dr. Robin Kanarek named professor of the year. Archivist [Greg Colati] encourages accessible history. Men's lacrosse continues losing streak. Softball splits double header, sailing finishes 2nd, tennis gets trounced. Gale-force winds plague track invitational. Men's baseball passes the mid-season test. Women's lacrosse comes out on top.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-04-20; UP055.025.025.00078 (Box 25)
    TCF [Tufts Christian Fellowship] decries derecognition, consults lawyer. Three Tufts students arrested in protests. Career services improves online resource. INQUIRY participants debate Olympic protocol. Campus leaders evaluate Harris' term. Freshman [Adam Carlis] hopes to spur campus activism. Softball sweeps games at Williams invitational. Men not on track vs. rival. Baseball splits weekend. Men's lacrosse kicks tail of mules. Colby toothless vs. Women's lax. Two jumbos qualify for N. Englands.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-04-27; UP055.025.025.00079 (Box 25)
    Students chose next president. Tufts researchers use animals to understand human aggression. Concert board explains decision process. Student clubs often in conflict with agendas of national affiliates. Tufts admits strongest class to date. Senator [Carl Jackson] promotes social justice, kills bugs. [Coach John] Casey not at bat to talk about baseball. Men's track washed out by coast guard. Women's track conquers at Conn. Women's lax sends camels to desert after loss. Lacrosse shoots down falcons. Softball wins two from Amherst, receives spot in NCAA field.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-03-04; UP055.025.025.00080 (Box 25)
- Tufts Observer, 2000 -- 2001; UP055.026; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series consists of loose copies of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from September 8, 2000 to October 12, 2001. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. The Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-09-08; UP055.026.026.00001 (Box 26)
    U.S. News Ranks Tufts 29th. New Alcohol Policy Impacts Student Life. Rev. McLennan Accepts Stanford Position. Fall Tufts-In-Ghana Program Cancelled, Spring Students Not Notified. TCU [Tufts Community Union] President Prankster Ponders Position. Putnam Has High Hopes For Young Runners, Expects To Finish in Top Ten [men's cross country].
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-09-15; UP055.026.026.00002 (Box 26)
    DiBiaggio Announces Plans to Leave. TCF [Tufts Christian Fellowship], Student Leaders Await Hearing. Tufts Establishes Middle Eastern Studies Major. With Move Dowling Hall Completed, Staff Adjusts to Influx of Students. Senior Reflects on Activities, Public Service. Women's Tennis Adds Season, Team Tryouts Competitive. Volleyball Looks To Improve. Men's X-C Runs Over the Competition at Saturday's Hayseed Classic.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-09-22; UP055.026.026.00003 (Box 26)
    Tufts' Use of Social Security Numbers Presents Possible Risk. Judiciary Candiates Debate. Genetics Study Seeks to Prevent Disease. Provost Proudly Presides Over Academics [Sol Gittleman]. Volleyball Volleys Through Easy Emmanuel. Women's Soccer Slips Against Middlebury's Slater. Football Coach Looks to Speed for Season's Success.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-09-29; UP055.026.026.00004 (Box 26)
    Power Surge Leaves Several Departments Without Email. Local Police Regulate Off-Campus Parties. Senators, Lee Hope To Alleviate Dewick TV Complaints. Computing Services Explains Bandwidth Cap. TUTV [Tufts University Television] President Produces Campus Programs [Don Schechter]. Women's Volleyball Struggles in MIT Tournament. Morwick [Kristen] Becomes New Cross Country Head Coach, Anticipates Good Season. Baseball Season Winds to Close With Playoffs. DiStaulo [Pete] Leads Team by Example [football]. Crew Benefits From Young Team. Crofton [Leslie] Gets First In Women's X-C. Men's Cross Country Comes in First at Saturday's Codfish Bowl.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-10-06; UP055.026.026.00005 (Box 26)
    Students Debate Police Over Social Scene Crackdown. Roberto [John] Leads Beautification Efforts. Local Students Enjoy Proximity to Hometown. Student Activists March in Boston. Tufts Polls Is Completed, Training To Begin. Sherwin [Martin] Explores America's Nuclear History. Soccer Delivers Third Win [Men's soccer]. Women's Soccer Rides Wave of Victory. Football Comeback Secures Its First Win. Women's Volleyball Dominates St. Joseph's, Loses Bates Invitational.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-10-13; UP055.026.026.00006 (Box 26)
    Cell Phones Used As Sole Phone Service Provider. Students Rally Protests Police Crackdown. Tufts Restricts Parking, Vehicle Ticketing Increases. Housing Market Favors Early Leases. Writing Professor Teaches Students To Choose [Michael Downing]. Alum Receives Discovery Award [Fran Sussner Rodgers]. Football Comes From Behind To Win. Volleyball Completes First Winning NESCAC [New England Small Colleges Athletic Conference] Weekend. Women's Soccer Faces Bumpy Road Trip.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-10-20; UP055.026.026.00007 (Box 26)
    TCF [Tufts Christian Fellowship] Ruling Allows Discrimination Against Belief, Not Identity. Senate Overturns Controversial Mandatory Meetings Decision. Parents' Events Highlight International Spirit. Hate Crimes Increase, Administration Responds. Third Sign Language Class Offered, Fulfills Language Requirement. Landmann [Dan] Brings Energetic Leadership to LCS [Leonard Carmichael Society]. Tufts Christian Fellowship vs. Julie Catalano Tufts Community Union Judiciary Unabridged Opinion - October 16, 2000. Football Falls Short in 4th Quarter Rally. Field Hockey Triumphs in Close Games. Women's C-Country Runs Well Against Highly Ranked Schools. Men's Soccer Kicks Over the Trinity Bantams. Volleyball Bounces Back in Bumpy NESCAC [New England Small Colleges Athletic Conference] Weekend.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-10-27; UP055.026.026.00008 (Box 26)
    Taliban Leader Defends Afghani Government at Fletcher. Rally Addresses Concerns About Campus Discrimination. Explorations Group Visits Director Kevin Smith. Administration Files Additional Charges Against Fraternities. Senate Vice President Moved by Movies, Race Issues [Eric Greenberg]. Tufts Homecoming 2000.Soccer Shuts out Cows, Builds Playoff Confidence [women's]. Field Hockey Wins In Overtime Game. Football Stays Hopeful Despite Loss.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-11-03; UP055.026.026.00009 (Box 26)
    Powell Addresses Middle East Crisis. New Groups Consider Recognition Policies. Students Find Differences Between Professional Ambulance Services, TEMS [Tufts Emergence Medical Service]. Junior Entertains Children With Theater Troupe [Sarah Marcus]. Volleyball Faces Disappointing Loss. Women's Tennis Finishes Strong Season. Jumbo Football Falls Short of Victory.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-11-10; UP055.026.026.00010 (Box 26)
    Fire Devastates Student Apartment. Diversity Proposals Considered. New Group Aims to Connect Students, Alumni. Compute Research Affords Students Corporate Experience. Professor Exemplifies Expression Through Movement [Roberta Pasternack]. Women's Volleyball Finishes Season at Even .500. Men's Soccer Wins First ECAC [East Coast Athletic Championships] Round. Women's Soccer Kicks Into Overdrive. Seniors Say Goodbye to Zinman in Hard-Fought Game [football].
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-11-17; UP055.026.026.00011 (Box 26)
    Students to Protest U.S. Army School. Online Registration Blocked by Traffic. LGBT [Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transsexual] Community Considers Transgendered Bathroom Implementation. Funding, Land Limitations Stall new Dorm Construction. Rosenberg [Doug] Displays Continuing Passion for Jazz. Soccer Heads to Final Four [Women's]. Men's Soccer Wins First ECAC [Eastern Colleges Athletic Conference] Championship. Football Loses to Middlebury; Seniors Cap off Disappointing Season. Field Hockey Loses in Semi-final Round.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-12-01; UP055.026.026.00012 (Box 26)
    Protesters Celebrate Victory After Two Day Sit-in. Presidential Search Underway. Search Continues for Hindi Instructor. Public Relations Targets High Schools. Therapist Massages Students' Worries Away [Larry Warnock]. Hockey Picks up Early Blowouts. Babson Beavers Beat Women's Basketball. Men's Basketball Stomps on Rams. Men's Track Has High Hopes.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-12-08; UP055.026.026.00013 (Box 26)
    TUTV [Tufts University Television] Receives $26,000 For Ten New Field Cameras. Judiciary Approves TCF [Tufts Christian Fellowship] Constitution. Dennett [Daniel] Studies Question of Computerized Consciousness. Trustee Deals With Major Campus Concerns [John Dowling]. The Puck Stops Here; Hockey Moves to 6-0. Goodman's [Emily] Scoring Fuels B-Ball Wins [women's basketball]. Captain's Corner: Dan Mahoney [hockey].
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-01-26; UP055.026.026.00014 (Box 26)
    Senate lobbies against parental access to grades. DiBiaggio, Hollister reinstate leadership class following positive student response. Presidential Search Committee seeks input from students. Addressing financial aid. Birthright Israel provides free trip. President looks back at changes, improvements, At the close of his Tufts career, John DiBiaggio praises University. Editorial: Financial Aid ought to rethink policies. Learning from mu mistakes. Opinion: In the Unlikely Event of an Emergency, Let There Be Light, This Old Car, Just Say No to Abstinence Education. On the town: Bartley's Burger Cottage Adds Character to Harvard Square, P.F. Chang's Does not Deliver. Jumbos jolted by Worcester State (hockey). Jumbos swim to undefeated streak, Tufts defeats Trinity and Wesleyan to stay at 6-0. Men's basketball bounces to improved record.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-02-02; UP055.026.026.00015 (Box 26)
    New interdisciplinary major attracts students. Former political journalist speaks of recent presidents. Departments differ in honors requirements. Student groups prepare preliminary budgets to present to TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate. Interim chaplain addresses gender, family issues, Patricia Kepler explored life and learning in her first 'reflections'. Editorials: Activities fee needs closer management, On-campus event demonstrates spirit, A manifesto to the Absurdist Party. Opinion: A Man's Man, Living for the Lumpless Potatoes, We're not Tufts: This is the Fletcher School. Lord Jeff's Reign over Men's Basketball. Hockey suffers tough loss. Women's Basketball jumps over Amherst.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-02-09; UP055.026.026.00016 (Box 26)
    Committees petition Trustees for new dorm, Administrators anticipate Trustee concerns of financing, demand. Tufts provides free shuttle bus to Boston. Facilities plans $1.8 million "Wrenovation". Applications on the rise for Early Decision. TRUCE [Tufts Religious Union for Cooperation and Ecumenism] pledges to unite religious groups on campus. Professor researches alcohol-related aggression, Klaus Miczek chairs a Committee on Animal Research and Ethics. Students volunteer at local afterschool adventures program. Editorials: In Dorms We Trustee, Senate Spending, Some Like it Hot. Opinion: The Primary Right to Choose, ECO [Environmental Consciousness Outreach]'s Doin' It in the Dark, Hodgon Math, Have You been tempted? On the town: Students Find Peet's Piss Poor. Balch Arena plays host to a Greek tragedy. Men's swimming finishes strong at 8-1, Despite defeat, Jumbos anticipate NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] championships. Colby, Bowdoin oust Jumbos, Lack of focus troubles Women's Basketball team.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-02-16; UP055.026.026.00017 (Box 26)
    Schools protest New England Division's sports policy, Students organize at Tufts to combat limited post-season play. Dorm security concerns arise after recent South Hall incidents. Senate seeks to improve World Civilizations Options. Faculty board to decide on creation of Film Studies minor. Trustees approve new dorm. Professor's lessons extend beyond Chemistry, Chris Morse will appear as only faculty member in "West Side Story". Editorials: World Sieve?, Size Matters, Fatal Error. Opinion: Banning Napster is a misguided solution. Of Cars and Men, Easy as F=ma, Paranoia in Houston Hall. Vaginal Discourse at Cohen. Hockey glides past competition. Panthers make a meal of Jumbos (men's basketball).
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-02-23; UP055.026.026.00018 (Box 26)
    Plans underway for Boston, College Avenue intersection. Tufts braces for rising energy costs. TASA [Tufts Association of South Asians] raises $70,000 for India victims. Students find non-European Study Abroad options limited. Tufts Police offer new student escort service. Pre-Med senior works with terminally ill children, Rebecca Rich serves as President of the Tufts Wind ensemble. Editorials: Turn off the Light on the Hill, Study Father Abroad, TTYL, LOL :-) (Talk to you later, Laugh out loud). Opinions: Witness an Execution, Plants and Humanity, Sticking to the SAT [Standardized Academics Test]. TASA [Tufts Association of South Asians] prepares for annual culture show. Jumbos exit early from tournament, White Mules knock out Women's Basketball in the first round. Basketball ends with four game skid. Hockey secures first place with win, Jumbos defeat New Hampshire College to raise record to 17-5-1.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-03-02; UP055.026.026.00019 (Box 26)
    Students propose structural changes, seek equal representation in Student-Faculty Committee. Fulbright finalists anticipate Study Abroad opportunities. EPIIC [Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship] Symposium tackles controversial topic of race. Nutrition school studies health of college lifestyle. Professor comes to discover Sociology through Nursing, Susan Ostrander focuses on Class, Race, and Gender in her courses. Editorials: Cooperation makes it happen, EPIIC [Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship] races ahead, Hit me baby. Opinion: Don't blame corporations for "Jackasses", The SAT [Standardized Academic Test] is not okay, Just looking for a fight, A tribute to Donella Meadows. Tufts' finest art collection is displayed at Cohen. Salve Regina upsets Jumbos in overtime, 6-5, Despite dominating season, Tufts unsuccessful in post-season play (hockey). Men's basketball finishes season 15-9, without reaching post-season.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-03-09; UP055.026.026.00020 (Box 26)
    New dean of Fletcher pledges to pursue academic excellence. Revised block schedule undergoes trial period. Engineering lecturer dies at 70. Tommy Hilfiger speaks about path to entrepreneurial success. Undergraduates present original research projects at symposium. Students plan activities to foster unity among graduating seniors. Choreographer takes dancers in new direction, head of Tufts Dance Collective Pat Girvin directs his final show. Editorials: Disturbing Coverage, The point of feminism, Behind the hair-rock era. Opinion: The Great Gun Debate, A closer look at Tufts' IR [International Relations] department, Removing SATs only treats the symptom, Losing my religion. Beelzebubs present their audiences with the 'next' best thing to a live show. 3Ps [Pen, Paint, and Pretzels] 'Whack the Bush' in this weekends Overmyer play. Baseball braces for tough season. Sailing starts Spring season at Navy, Nationally-ranked Women's, Co-ed and race teams anticipate strong start. Spring preview: Men's Tennis. Spring Preview: Women's Lacrosse. Spring Preview: Men's Lacrosse.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-01; UP055.026.026.00021 (Box 26)
    April fools edition
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-13; UP055.026.026.00022 (Box 26)
    TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate closes year of transformation. Forum highlights differences in gay and evangelical views. Concert board secures well-known band for Spring Fling. JumboScope offers students interactive multimedia experience. TUPD [Tufts University Police Department] Sergeant brings community together, Doug Mazzola addresses crime prevention and awareness issues. Editorials: A Wise Tradition, For the kids, Lessons of Laundry. Opinion: Fletcher students should get off their high horses, Whoring yourself for a resume, Rowing is rough but rewarding and keeps 'em coming back for more. 'West Side' rumble erupts on Cohen stage. Panthers prey on Jumbos, 13-8, Men's lacrosse drops to 5-4 record after defeat. Baseball drops to .500 overall, remains 2-0 in NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] conference. Women Athletes prove they have got game.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-06; UP055.026.026.00023 (Box 26)
    Students to vote on Controversial Amendment, Revised Senate Constitution gives culture representatives voting rights. Professor teaches with [Albert] Gore. Housing policies undergo changes, problems remain. Tufts launches sexual assault help line. English professor encourages students to criticize, In his twenty-second year, Lee Edelman praises community, students. Editorials: Cooperation makes it happen, Sex, ads and MTV. Opinion: Finding you niche, 10 Reasons why we need a gradeless institution, Campaign finance reform gives power to the people, A Medical Nightmare. Jumbos Bash Buchaneers. 17-3 [baseball]. Captain's Corner: Dan Kollar [lacrosse].
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-20; UP055.026.026.00024 (Box 26)
    Engineering students win first place in Environmental Contest. Majority of Senators run uncontested. 'Radix' joins campus media, New liberal journal uses radical consensus method. Professor searches for more efficient ways to store electrical energy. Professor takes learning beyond the classroom, Lee Vigilant makes impression on students in many programs. TCU [Tufts Community Union] presidential candidates publish platforms. Editorials: A pathetic turn-out, [David] Attanasio missed the joke?, What's in a name? Opinion: Building Community a all costs. The Source: Primarily bigots. Fletcher replies to unfounded claims. Softball splits double header, [Jodie] Moreau pitches gem to keep Jumbos undefeated in NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference]. [Jon] Bram and [Sonny] Kathpalia Triumph for tennis, Strong performance by freshmen put Jumbos one win from .500.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-25; UP055.026.026.00025 (Box 26)
    Election issue. Campus leaders say what it takes to be TCU [Tufts Community Union] president. Candidate profile: Eric Greenberg. Candidate profile: Michelle Shelton. Vote Michelle Shelton. Farewell address: A culture of cynicism. Campaign goals from the candidates.
  - Tufts Observer, 2001-04-27; UP055.026.026.00026 (Box 26)